Guide to the Asian Women United Oral History Collection OH.074
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Asian Women United Oral History Collection
2008-2009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Chu, I-Ting Emily
OH.074
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
Asian Women United (AWU) was a New York-based nonprofit organization formed in 1978. With a distinctly feminist point of view, the organization sought to support, educate and empower Asian-American women. AWU explored Asian-American women's history and culture and mobilized community women in the political arena. The Asian Women United Oral History Collection is comprised of thirteen interviews that document the individual stories and contributions of members. I-Ting Emily Chu conducted three of the oral histories for the Fall 2008 Oral History Seminar, taught by NYU professor Rachel Bernstein. Others were taken by Chu as part of her work at the the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Interviews collected by I-Ting Emily Chu on behalf of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. The accession number associated with this collecction is 2008.060.
Arrangement
Interviews are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Asian Women United (AWU) was a New York-based nonprofit organization formed in 1978. With a distinctly feminist point of view, the organization sought to support, educate and empower Asian-American women. AWU explored Asian-American women's history and culture and mobilized community women in the political arena.
The Asian Women United Oral History Collection was taken to document the individual stories and contributions of members and to supplement the materials in the Asian Women United Records and Photographs (TAM 320) at the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives. I-Ting Emily Chu conducted three oral histories for the Fall 2008 Oral History Seminar, taught by NYU professor Rachel Bernstein. Others were taken by Chu as part of her work at the Tamiment Library.
Related Archival Materials
Asian Women United Records and Photographs (TAM 320)
Scope and Content Note
The collection is comprised of thirteen interviews documenting the lives and activism of members of Asian Women United.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Asian American women -- Social conditions.; Asian Americans -- Civil rights.; Asian Americans -- Economic conditions.; Asian American women; Asian Women United
- Tomie Arai, Apr 8, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_bb55fc09f2bf13df327e616d34802517, Dvd data_value_missing_e526935a5982cb68a2ee253ec0b86689)
- Mary Chin, Feb 7, 2009 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_236ba1cf47662ebe8425ea298b194a8b, Cd data_value_missing_d165cb59f7c10d38d364adc7af1fbf21)
- Aiyoung Choi, Mar 11, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_07afe01440bf0dd2808310624af966ba, Dvd data_value_missing_ea03305a02a112236ba1bc5c1ff23e58)
- Goldie Chu, May 19, 2009 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_0ef02e29b39f7b2777d83938fcb4cafb, Cd data_value_missing_bdc89877ee8eba7d42557e29835af3bb)
- Jacqueline (Jackie) Huey, Nov 3, 2008 (Box 1, Item data_value_missing_624f7d1015829423fd6368ebab5aa01b, Dvd data_value_missing_e413d94f445b3fcddcd8869950aeb3bd, Cd data_value_missing_d5aeab474b18e57afa265e43e75baab0, Cd data_value_missing_1b8c2ea4e490fe4b8c91f8e9a4104491)
- Sokie Lee, Mar 9, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_01c95b83c2c6c10b491cda66dd5f3e43, Dvd data_value_missing_87c1b2f0b1a876bc909ed99a72d6b898)
- Susan Louie, May 15, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_6b20e0b7624069d59bb1e8afabac483c, Dvd data_value_missing_75fe27dc9c8d7fe675fa79ed2d4be6da)
- Lily Moy, May 12, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_6aa0036a8ae1e8d2e304537158942622, Dvd data_value_missing_6047511c64ef8bcd484a16a3e235cd99)
- Suki Ports, May 21, 2009 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_e439c9c218ccb1c1c1e1e6d00e6df0cc, Cd data_value_missing_044c98308b4133e088236b80862b7685)
- Ruby Tsang, Mar 12, 2009 (Box 1, Cd data_value_missing_26623fce38abbd4d33168003738af536, Dvd data_value_missing_b36a8086e09eeb641cdda7ee7877fe6f)
- Joyce B. Wong, Nov 7, 2008 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_39a63cc6e82b59423ded2716ec548440, Item data_value_missing_0b9509cf4e4dcb89e1ec76bf7ae8fc48, Cd data_value_missing_7d3ad0c70876f175d20e58139f2b38ed, Cd data_value_missing_1651fe56cfa61056f6ce6cdbf537769a)
- Susan Wong, May 14, 2009 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_c1359fe5737823f999d5579d4a3e7e95, Cd data_value_missing_90a3f148ffebf30e568a6833533aedd1)
- Liz Young, Oct 14, 2008 (Box 1, Dvd data_value_missing_9b7d65eeb4ea57e0861b5c5a502f573f, Item data_value_missing_b4c989f2ee6a3fbb4c8580632e891111, Cd data_value_missing_f0f3a273b9d6fa05fb8a4fbcf8067c18, Cd data_value_missing_5b3dd9ed6193c5e1faef7800af02a7bf)